fastcomet.com 2019-12-21

# Privacy Policy | FastComet

The following Privacy Policy ("Policy") is intended to describe to you how FastComet, Inc and its affiliates ("FastComet," "we," "our" or "us") collect, use, maintain and share information in connection with your use of our websites (including www.fastcomet.com, my.fastcomet.com), services, and applications (collectively, the "Services"). It also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and otherwise take control of your personal data that we process. This Privacy Policy (the "Privacy Policy") does not apply to information you, as a customer, may process when using our Services.

FastComet cares about your privacy and is committed to developing long lasting relationships that are built on trust and would never intentionally violate that trust. For this reason, we collect and use personal data only as it might be needed for us to deliver to you our world-class products and services. We may collect and receive information about users of our Services ("users," "you," or "your") from various sources, including: information you provide through your user account on the Services (your "Account") if you sign up for the Services; your use of the Services; your Support Tickets, Live Chat or other support communication channels; from third-party websites, services, and partners. Your personal data includes information such as:

  * Name
  * Address
  * Telephone number
  * Date of birth
  * Email address
  * Other data collected that could directly or indirectly identify you.

We recommend that you read this Privacy Policy in full to ensure you are fully informed. The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received. If at any time you have questions about our practices or any of your rights described below, you may reach our Data Protection Officer ("DPO") and our dedicated team that supports this office by contacting us at [privacy@fastcomet.com](mailto:privacy@fastcomet.com). This inbox is actively monitored and managed so that we can deliver an experience that you can confidently trust.

### 1\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT

**Information You Provide**

In order for you to utilize our Services and other features of our Site, we will ask you for some of your personal data (e.g. contact information, name, etc.). The amount and type of information that we gather depends on the nature of the interaction.

**Account Registration**. Account related information is collected in association with your use of our Service, such as account number, purchases, when products renew or expire, information requests, and customer service requests and notes or details explaining what you asked for and how we responded. When you sign up for an Account, we may ask for your contact information, including items such as name, company name, address, email address, and telephone number. In addition, to register a domain name, you may be asked to provide this information for the registrant, administrative contact, technical contact and billing contact of the domain name (collectively, "Domain Name Registration Information"), for submission to the appropriate domain registry or registration database.

**Payment Information**. When you add your financial account information to your Account, that information is transmitted directly (in encrypted form) to our third-party payment processor. When transferring personal information a security icon will appear in your browser. We do not store your financial account information on our systems; however, we have access to, and may retain, subscriber information through our third-party payment processor.

**Communications**. If you contact us directly, you may be required to give us additional information to assist us in resolving their questions, or to assist us in our business, such as your name, email address, phone number, the contents of the message and/or attachments you may send us, and any other information you may choose to provide. The personal information we collect depends on the type of service, support, or sales inquiry. If any other additional personal information is requested from you, other than the needed information during the account registration process, the reasons why you are asked to provide it, will be made clear to you at the point we ask you to provide such.

**Information We Collect When You Use Our Services.**

**Web server logs**. As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. In addition, when you use our Services, we may collect certain information automatically from your device. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, clickstream data, landing page, and referring URL. We use this information gathered about you from our Site to help personalize search results, diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Site. We also gather broad demographic information from this data to help us improve our Site and make your browsing and purchasing experience more enjoyable. This is not linked to any personally identifiable information, except as necessary to prevent fraud or abuse on our system.

**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**. Like many companies, we use browser cookies on this web site. We send one or more cookies - a small file containing a string of characters - to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. These cookies and similar technologies enable us to analyze trends, administer the Site, to track your browsing behavior, links clicked, items purchased, your device type, and to collect various data, including analytics. We may also automatically collect information about your use of features of our Services, about the functionality of our Services, frequency of visits, and other information related to your interactions with the Services. This allows us to provide you with more relevant product offerings, a better experience on our sites and mobile applications, and to collect, analyze and improve the performance of our Services. We may track your use across different websites and services.

More specifically, we use different types of cookies for different purposes: (i) "required cookies" are necessary for our website to work properly, (ii) "performance cookies" allow us to analyze how Visitors use our website so we can measure and improve the performance of our website, (iii) "functional cookies" allow us to remember choices you may have made on our website, and (iv) "advertising cookies" are used to present ads that are relevant to your interests. We may utilize cookies to track referrals from internal and external affiliates, as well as advertising campaigns. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. For more information on Cookie and Tracking as well as direct control over our website Cookies, you may review our Cookie Policy.

**Usage of our Services**. When you use our Services, we may collect information about your engagement with and utilization of our Services, such as processor and memory usage, storage capacity, navigation of our Services, and system-level metrics. We use this data to operate the Services, maintain and improve the performance and utilization of the Services, develop new features, protect the security and safety of our Services and our customers, and provide customer support. We also use this data to develop aggregate analysis and business intelligence that enable us to operate, protect, make informed decisions, and report on the performance of our business.

**Customer Surveys**. We may periodically conduct customer surveys. Participation in our customer surveys is voluntary. However, we encourage our users to participate in these surveys because they provide us with important information that helps us improve the types of services we offer and how we provide them to you. Your personal information, if provided, will remain confidential, even if the survey is conducted by a third party service provider on our behalf.

**Testimonials**. You may provide us with a written or verbal endorsement of our Services in connection with your use of the Services ("Endorsement"). The Endorsement will be the actual first-hand account of your experience using our Services and we may, at our discretion, use the Endorsement to promote our Services in-person, in print, online, and all other media. We may also edit the Endorsement for brevity or other reasons, so long as it is consistent with your original Endorsement. In connection with our use of your Endorsement, you hereby agree that we may use your first name, last initial, home state, voice or likeness, and/or contact information in connection with its publication of the Endorsement. If, at any time, you want us to stop using your Endorsement, please contact us at [privacy@fastcomet.com](mailto:privacy@fastcomet.com).

**Social Media**. Our website includes social media features (such as the Facebook "Like" button). These features may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets may be hosted by a third party or directly on our website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the feature.

**Information We Receive from Third Parties.**

**Third-Party Accounts**. If you choose to link our Services to a third-party account, we will receive information about that account, such as your authentication token from the third-party account, to authorize linking. If you wish to limit the information available to us, you should visit the privacy settings of your third-party accounts to learn about your options.

**Third-Party Partners**. We may also receive publicly available information about you from our third-party partners and combine it with data that we have about you. We do this to enhance our ability to serve you, to tailor our products and services to you, and to offer you opportunities to purchase products or services that we believe may be of interest to you.

**Information collected by our customers.**

Our customers may collect personal data in connection with the Services we provide to them. FastComet's customers control the personal data they collect, and FastComet will not use or disclose that personal data except as authorized or directed by the customer in the course of our provision of the Services. If your personal data is controlled by one of our customers and you have concerns about the way that data is managed, please contact that customer directly.

### 2\. HOW WE USE INFORMATION

We use Personal Data to conduct business, provide information and support for products and services, better understand your needs and interests, refine and develop our business, improve services, personalize communications and ensure a quality experience for users of the Website and Services. For example, we may use your information to:

  * Provide, operate, and maintain our Services;
  * Measure, analyze and improve our products and services, the effectiveness of our Website (and related websites)s, and our advertising and marketing;
  * Understand and analyze how you use our Services and what products and services are most relevant to you;
  * Develop new products, services, features, and functionality;
  * Communicate, interact and build our relationship with you with you, either directly or through one of our partners, including for customer service;
  * Communicate with you from time to time relevant promotions, important updates and other information about the services we provide;
  * Help identify and communicate offers of products, programs and services that may be of interest to you;
  * Personalize content and advertising;
  * Follow up on survey answers. FastComet may also contact you to highlight the changes FastComet makes in response to your feedback.;
  * Process your transactions;
  * Detect and prevent fraud and abuse of our Services and systems; and
  * For compliance purposes, including enforcing our Terms of Service, or other legal rights, or as may be required by applicable laws and regulations or requested by any judicial process or governmental agency.

### 3\. HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION

We only share your personal data as necessary for any third party to provide the services as requested or as needed on our behalf. These third parties (and any subcontractors) are subject to strict data processing terms and conditions and are prohibited from utilizing, sharing or retaining your personal data for any purpose other than as they have been specifically contracted for (or without your consent).

**Vendors and Service Providers.** We may share information with third-party vendors and service providers that provide services on our behalf, such as helping to provide our Services, for promotional and/or marketing purposes, and to provide you with information relevant to you such as product announcements, software updates, special offers, or other information.  
Aggregate Information. Where legally permissible, we may use and share information about users with our partners in aggregated or de-identified form that can't reasonably be used to identify you.

**Targeted Advertising**. We work with third-party advertising partners to show you ads based on your activities on our webpages, and other websites, and based on the products you currently own. These advertising partners may set and access their own cookies, pixel tags, and similar technologies on our Services, and they may otherwise collect or have access to information about such activities in order to provide you with advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests, and to measure advertising effectiveness

FastComet may utilize third party platforms to provide web-based and email-based advertisements for FastComet services after a user has visited and left FastComet's website. FastComet and its advertising partners comply with "opt out" signals provided either by a user's web browser automatically, by a user manually opting-out of web-based advertisements at Client area -> Personal Details -> Privacy and Security section, or by a user clicking the "unsubscribe" link in any promotional email.

**Analytics**. FastComet uses web analytics services to improve the usability and design of our customer experience. These tools place persistent cookies in your browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit our website. Each cookie cannot be used by anyone other than the service provider (ex: Google for Google Analytics). Google provides some additional privacy options regarding its Analytics cookies at <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>.

**Business Transfers**. Information may be disclosed and otherwise transferred to any potential acquirer, successor, or assignee as part of any proposed merger, acquisition, debt financing, sale of assets, or similar transaction, or in the event of insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership in which information is transferred to one or more third parties as one of our business assets.

**As Required By Law and Similar Disclosures.** We may also share information to (i) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process, or governmental request; (ii) enforce this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations hereof; (iii) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues; (iv) respond to your requests; or (v) protect our rights, property or safety, our users and the public. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and spam/malware prevention.

**With Your Consent**. We may share information with your consent.

### 4\. LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING PERSONAL INFORMATION

Our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it.

However, we will normally collect personal information from you only (i) where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you; (ii) where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your rights; or (iii) where we have your consent to do so. We have a legitimate interest in operating our Services and communicating with you as necessary to provide these Services, for example when responding to your queries, improving our platform, undertaking marketing, or for the purposes of detecting or preventing illegal activities.

In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you or may otherwise need the personal information to protect your vital interests or those of another person.

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contract with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information).

### 5\. THIRD-PARTY SERVICES

You may access other third-party services through the Services, for example by clicking on links to those third-party services from within the Services. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices of these third-party services, and we encourage you to carefully review their privacy policies.

### 6\. SECURITY

FastComet is committed to protecting your information. To do so, we employ a variety of security technologies and measures designed to protect information from unauthorized disclosure, misuse, alteration or loss. The measures we use, including and not limited to: physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online, are designed to provide a level of security appropriate to the risk of processing your personal information. However, please bear in mind that the Internet cannot be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

### 7\. DATA RETENTION

We retain personal information we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate legal or business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax, or accounting requirements).

These might include retention periods:

  * mandated by law, contract or similar obligations applicable to our business operations;
  * for preserving, resolving, defending or enforcing our legal/contractual rights; or
  * needed to maintain adequate and accurate business and financial records.

In order for us to fulfil our terms of service, FastComet will retain personal data for at least 30 days after service cancellation request. Clients have the right to execute their Right To Be Forgotten via the Client area -> Personal Details -> Privacy and Security section. Upon receiving such request, personal data will be removed except such required to comply with applicable legal, tax, or accounting requirements.

### 8\. ACCESS

To easily access, view, update, delete or port your personal data (where available), or to update your subscription preferences, please sign into your Account via your Client Area -> Personal Details section. If you make a request to delete your personal data and that data is necessary for the products or services you have purchased, the request will be honored only to the extent it is no longer necessary for any Services purchased or required for our legitimate business purposes or legal or contractual record keeping requirements. If you terminate your Account, any public activity on your Account prior to deletion may remain stored on our servers and may remain accessible to the public.

To protect your privacy and security, we may also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before updating or removing your information. The information you provide us may be archived or stored periodically by us according to backup processes conducted in the ordinary course of business for disaster recovery purposes. Your ability to access and correct your information may be temporarily limited where access and correction could: inhibit FastComet's ability to comply with a legal obligation; FastComet's ability to investigate, make or defend legal claims; result in disclosure of personal information about a third party; or result in breach of a contract or disclosure of trade secrets or other proprietary business information belonging to FastComet or a third party.

### 9\. YOUR DATA PROTECTION RIGHTS UNDER THE GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (GDPR)

If you are a resident of the EEA, you have the following data protection rights:

A **right of access** to a copy of the information comprised in their personal data; FastComet clients can access and edit their profile personal information via their Client Area -> Personal details section. In addition, you can request a copy of the information via the Subject Access Request section in your Client Area -> Privacy and Security -> Subject Access Request. In addition, you can object to the processing of your personal information, ask us to restrict the processing of your personal information, or request portability of your personal information. Again, you can exercise these rights by emailing [privacy@fastcomet.com](mailto:privacy@fastcomet.com).

A **right to prevent processing for direct marketing** ; You can withdraw your consent from having your personal data used for marketing purposes via your Client Area -> Privacy and Security -> Privacy Settings. You can also exercise this right by clicking on the "Unsubscribe" or "opt-out" link in the marketing emails we send you.

Similarly, if we have collected and process your personal information with your consent, then you can **withdraw your consent** at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect the processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.

You have the **right to complain to a data protection authority** about our collection and use of your personal information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority.

We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

You have the right to **withdraw your consent for these Privacy and Security policies** in any time via your client area -> Personal Details -> Privacy and Security. In case you withdraw your consent from these points we will not be able to continue providing any type of service and you have the right to discontinue your service or/and proceed with your Right To Be Forgotten.

Upon executing your **Right to be Forgotten** you understand and agree that:

  * your client area and personal details will be permanently removed
  * your hosting accounts and services will be cancelled and terminated
  * all your files, databases, email accounts and any other type of data hosted on your hosting account will be permanently removed
  * your invoices and billing data will be no longer accessible
  * your payment and credit card information will be permanently deleted
  * your support tickets and any information included in them will be permanently removed

### 10\. YOUR CHOICES

You can use some of the features of the Services without registering, thereby limiting the type of information that we collect.

You may unsubscribe from receiving certain promotional emails from us. If you wish to do so, simply follow the instructions found at the end of the email. Even if you unsubscribe, we may still contact you for informational, transactional, account-related, or similar purposes.

Many browsers have an option for disabling cookies, which may prevent your browser from accepting new cookies or enable selective use of cookies. Please note that, if you choose not to accept cookies, some features and the personalization of our Services may no longer work for you. You will continue to receive advertising material but it will not be tailored to your interests.

### 11\. AGE RESTRICTIONS

Our Services are available for purchase only for those over the age of 13. Our Services are not targeted to, intended to be consumed by or designed to entice individuals under the age of 13. FastComet does not intentionally collect information from children under the age of 13, and children under 13 are prohibited from using our Services. If FastComet becomes aware that personal information from a child under the age of 13 has been collected, FastComet will use all reasonable efforts to delete such information from its database. If you know of or have reason to believe anyone under the age of 13 has provided us with any personal data, please contact us.

### 12\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes to this Privacy Policy and any other places we deem appropriate, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our terms of service page. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### 13\. INTERNATIONAL DATA TRANSFERS

FastComet operates globally as a business. We may transfer personal information to countries other than the country in which the data was originally collected. These countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. When we transfer your personal information to other countries, we will protect that information as described in this Privacy Policy.

**Contact Us**

In case you need additional information related to these Privacy Policy, please feel free to email us at [privacy@fastcomet.com](mailto:privacy@fastcomet.com).

_We will respond to all requests, inquiries or concerns within thirty (30) days._

The data controller of your personal information is FastComet, LLC.
